So here's a way to define is_palindrome. So we're taking
接下来就是定义回文过程的一种方法 我们需要
a single string as an output, I will call it s,
输入一个字符串 我把它叫做 s
and we're first going to test the base case. So the
然后我们首先进行基本情况的判断 所以
base case was to see if the string is empty, we
基本情况就是当输入的字符串为空字符串时  我们
should return true right away. So we can do that
应该马上返回逻辑真的结果 所以我们可以
with an if. We are gonna check if s is equal
用 if 语句实现判断 我们将检验 s 是否等于
to the empty string, and if it is, we return true,
空字符串 如果它等于空字符串的话 我们就返回逻辑真的值
that's our base case. For the else, we have the recursive
这就是基本情况的 if 子句部分 对于 else 子句部分 我们要开始递归情况的判断
case so now we need to do the test of the first and the last characters to
所以我们现在需要进行字符串第一个字符和最后一个字符的测试
see if they match. And we can do that
看它们的值是否相等 我们可以实现它
using the string indexing operators, as 0 gets us
通过字符串的索引操作符  我们可以从 s[0] 得到
the first character, s negative 1 gets us the
字符串的第一个字符  s[-1] 可以为我们取得
last character. If they match, then we need to
字符串的最后一个字符 如果这两个字符相等的话 那我们需要
check the rest of the string. If they didn't
测试字符串的剩余部分 如果它们不相等的话
match and let's finish the didn't match case first.
让我们先完成不符合以上情况时的代码
So if they didn't match then we know it is
所以如果它们不相等 我们就知道它不是
a palindrome, because we found a place where the first and
回文 因为我们发现了第一个字符
the last character did not match, so we should return
和最后一个字符不相等的情况 所以该过程应该返回
false right away. If they did match, well then we have
逻辑假的值 如果它们相等的话 那么我们就有
the harder problem. We need to do the recursive call
更困难的问题要解决 我们需要进行递归调用
to check all the other letters in the strings still form
校验字符串中的其他所有字符是否仍然
a palindrome. So this was our starting string. It had
属于回文 这是我们的初始字符串 它由
all these characters in it. We checked that this one matches
这么多字符组成 我们已经测试了这个字符是否
this one, so now what we need to do is take the rest of the string and check
匹配这个字符 现在我们要做的是对字符串剩余部分进行校验
if this is a palindrome. So that'll be a
判断剩余部分是否构成回文 这将是一个
recursive call, so we're going to return the result, of calling
递归调用 所以我们将返回这样的结果
is_palindrome. But instead of passing in s, what we
也就是调用 is_palindrome 过程本身 但不同于输入字符串 s 的是 我们
want to do is pass in the string starting from
要输入的是 s[1:-1] 子串
position 1 of s, so removing the first character,
也就是移去第一个字符
and ending at position negative 1, removing the last character.
然后以 -1 作结尾 也就是移去最后一个字符
And remember with our indexing, the last value here is
要记住我们索引的用法 这里的最后一个字符 s[-1] 是不包括在内的
not included. So by having the last index as negative
所以这里的最后一个索引值取 -1
1, that removes the final letter of the string. So
它就移去了字符串的最后一个字符
the first thing to test is the base case. So
我们首先要测试的是基本情况的判断
we'll pass in the empty string. And the empty string
我们输入空字符串 而空字符串
is a palindrome, so it should give us the result
属于回文 所以这个过程应该返回给我们的值是
true, which it does. Let's try the single letter string,
逻辑真 结果正是如此 让我们尝试一下单字符的字符串
a, that's also a palindrome. It's the same backwards and forwards.
a 它也是回文 正反向读都是同一个字符
And so we also get the value true, if we try say string ab, which is not a
然后我们也是得到逻辑真的结果 如果我们尝试输入 ab 字符串的话 也就是不属于
palindrome. We get false. As a longer test, if we
回文 我们得到了逻辑假的结果 做更长字符的测试 如果我们
try a level, we should get true. Which we do. And, let's try
尝试输入 level 我们应该得到逻辑真的结果 结果正确 然后我们尝试
one of the most famous palindromes, amanaplanacanalpanama.
最著名的一个回文 amanaplanacanalpanama
And we should get True which we do.
然后我们应该得到逻辑真的值 结果正是如此
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[无声音]